Finding Aid for the Lisa Aron Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Lisa Aron Collection
1932-1965
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0651
.42 linear_feet
Biography/History
Lisa Aron was born in 1968 in Bronx, New York. She has lived in England and Africa. When her father was a child escaped with his family from Nazi Germany and fled to Kenya. When he was an adult, he immigrated to the United States. Lisa became aware of the importance of civil, political, economic, social and cultural rights while living in Kenya, under a dictatorship. The need to combat prejudice, intolerance and racism was taken into account when she wrote the manuscript, Keyhole: The Politics of War Behind Closed Doors.
This collection was donated in 2007 by Lisa Aron, author of the manuscript.
Scope and Contents
This .42 linear foot collection contains one original, handwritten, family history about World War II, Nazi Germany, Auschwitz Concentration Camp, and the Aftermath of the War. The collection is divided by chapters.
- War on the Horizon, 1932-1945 (Folder Chapter 1)
- Escape from Auschwitz, 1943 (Folder Chapter 2)
- Flames of Auschwitz, 1943 (Folder Chapter 3)
- Return to Auschwitz, 1944 (Folder Chapter 4)
- Liberation of Auschwitz, 1945 (Folder Chapter 5)
- In the Hands of the Allies, 1946 (Folder Chapter 6)
- After the War, 1944 (Folder Chapter 7)
- Hadamar: The Roots of Evil, 1941 (Folder Chapter 8)
- Fugitive, 1945 (Folder Chapter 9)
- Journey into Exile, 1946 (Folder Chapter 10)
- Survival in Siberia, 1945 (Folder Chapter 11)
- Against the System, 1946 (Folder Chapter 12)
- Stranger in Poland, 1946-1947 (Folder Chapter 13)
- Pursuit of Justice (New York), 1965 (Folder Chapter 14)